Daniel Skowroński

@ daniel@skowron.ski

4 +48 507-188-312

◊ Krakow, Poland

% blog.dsinf.net

in linkedin.com/in/daniel-skowronski

O github.com/danielskowronski

ABOUT ME

My main fields of interest (both professionally and as a hobby) are systems architecture, administration, computer networks and cybersecurity. I refer to myself as hacker (in original meaning of that word but also as whitehat researcher).

I have experience in many stages of computer system lifecycle - not only in typical business roles but also as fullstack freelancer as well as all-in-one IT guy on festivals and in students' association. That gives me advantage of being able to understand customer and business needs and manage resources (including time) with care. Another aspect of my career story - work in operations jobs allowed me to learn how to work under time pressure in disaster scenarios.

I'm advocate of Bill Gate's words "I choose a lazy person to do a hard job, because a lazy person will find an easy way to do it" - and really prefer to automate everything. I'm also constant learner - not only mastering current skills but also discovering new approaches and technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Site Reliability Engineer in Big Data

Grand Parade part of William Hill

July 2020 - Ongoing

I'm building tools and processes to ensure the reliability and availability of Big Data platform and data processing. Technology stack includes on-premise Linux VMs, AWS (EKS), Apache Airflow, NiFi, Docker and Terraform. I'm also part of on-call support that responds 24/7 to incidents within platform.

Senior DevOps Engineer

Prescient Co

M October 2019 – July 2020

◊ Krakow, Poland

My job was to be a bridge between Development and IT Operations departments - maintaining systems to keep High Availability and security together with meeting business goals. Important parts of this chapter in my career are implementing Infrastructure-as-a-Code paradigm, introducing new operating system (Linux) and containerization systems (Kubernetes) into existing ecosystem.

Linux Platform Engineer

Motorola Solutions Systems

May 2019 - October 2019

As software developer in Dimetra Platform team I was responsible for the development of management and deployment tools for Linux platforms, as well as virtualization using VMware and KVM solutions.

I was also responsible for lab environment.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Linux Ansible Python Networks AWS



STRENGTHS

Development

Python bash PowerShell awk
Perl SQL Go C# x86 assembly

LETEX JavaScript

• Virtualization and containerization

Proxmox VMware vSphere

KVM (libvirt) Docker LXC

Kubernetes (Rancher) AWS

DevOps/automation tools

Ansible Jenkins Azure Pipelines

Elasticsearch Grafana

Databases

MSSQL MySQL PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

Computer Science

Jagiellonian University in Cracow

2014 - 2016

LANGUAGES

Polish English



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONT.)

Platform Operations Engineer

Akamai Technologies

I July 2016 - May 2019

Y Krakow, Poland

My responsibilities in Network Operations Command Center included responding to real time issues with entire Akamai platform - from routine hardware problems to global routing or capacity incidents which require immediate action. I participated in maintaining general network health, resolving configuration defects, performing network maintenance works and responding to outside communication with other NOCs and service providers.

Since 2018 I worked on senior level assignments which included approving potentially dangerous nonstandard operations, being part of incident coordination and deploying configuration changes. I also developed several software solutions that helped multiple departments in every day work.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

System Administrator

Computer Science Students' Association - KSI UJ

December 2014 - January 2018

◊ Krakow, Poland

My role as SysAdmin was to keep our network working and secure, maintain servers belonging to KSI including critical infrastructure (mail, DNS), develop applications that were used by management board, and supervise server room.

Another task of Administrator in KSI was to cooperate with network administrators of university.

Secretary of the Board

Computer Science Students' Association - KSI UJ

For 2 academic years I was also Secretary of the Board in KSI. As active member of board I also participated in organizing various events on UJ like *Malopolska Noc Naukowców* (Night of Scientists) and *Festiwal Nauki* (Science Festival).

Chief Information Officer

Academic IT Festival - SFI

math display="block" December 2014 - July 2017" December 2014 - July 2017

◊ Krakow, Poland

I was member of logistics team, Chief Information Officer and web developer involved in development of contest application (PHP, later Erlang) and DevOps (Git, CI).

I also acted as SysAdmin being responsible for network infrastructure during event and helpdesk engineer dealing with end users.

IT Coordinator

Theatre Festival "Zwierciadla"

🛗 September 2012 - May 2014

♥ Lublin, Poland

"Zwierciadla" is high school theatre festival organized by students. Since 2013 I was responsible for it's website and other IT and logistics related tasks like network configuration, helpdesk, coordinating multimedia processing and publishing etc.

That experience gave me early opportunity to learn team work and responsibility in the face of deadlines.

OTHERS

- Layer2 and Layer3 network maintenance and management (Cisco, Juniper, HP)
- TCP/IP and higher level protocols debugging (Wireshark)
- · security & whitehat hacking
- electronics

INTERESTS

- cybersecurity (whitehat-hacking)
- embedded systems
- electronics
- cloud computing
- amateur photography
- Japanese culture

GDPR

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the European Parliament's and Council of the European Union Regulation on the Protection of Natural Persons as of 27 April 2016, with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (Data Protection Directive)